<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[ Enterprise Applications Strategy ]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[ Enterprise Applications Strategy ]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 16:23:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Log In / 500px]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Log In / 500px</h1><p>500px lets you create stunning professional photo portfolios, find friends, express yourself and connect with people like you.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/c88a702192cdfb4e41a8e7bc85f583353cca3b3e.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://500px.com/manage/portfolio/peoplempc#</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5dd45202-e4c3-4f86-95a5-7631a7220c1f</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 15:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Search Quality search is the backbone of productivity. Slack allows users to search through titles, as well as search within shared documents and metadata. Search results can be filtered by their relevancy, how recently they occurred, or by what file type you may be looking for. Or, you can simply browse files if that's what you're looking for.  However, the key to productive search in slack is the use of modifiers. Much like what you'll find in Gmail's search, these modifiers further filter search results to get you the answer more quickly. The following modifiers are available for search.  From - When you're looking for content from a specific team member To - For something sent to a channel, group, or direct message In - For content within a channel, group, or direct message After - Something sent after a certain date Before - Something sent before a certain date On - Sent on a certain date During - Something sent during a month or year Has - Contains a star or a link Type the modifier with a colon following it, like "from:" and add what you want to include.  Integrations Users can connect some of the apps and tools they already use in their workflow to Slack through its integrations feature. Common apps such as Dropbox, Github, Google Calendar, Jira, and many others. If you have some programming skills you can also build your own integrations or customize them to your liking.  For example, you can integrate Twitter to have specific tweets post to certain channels. This works well for companies that handle customer service requests through social media. Also, integrating Google services like Hangouts allows you to start hangouts directly from a Slack channel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/search-quality-search-is-the-backbone-of-productivity-slack/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4140998a-5718-42b8-91de-be8a83d5f726</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 15:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Secure File Sharing Plans and Pricing | Box]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Secure File Sharing Plans and Pricing | Box</h1><p>Learn more about Box pricing plans for personal, starter, business and enterprise plans, plus Enterprise Key Management and Box Governance</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/dcacffa9cb1c2b041dedb007de3d24b9fee73087.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.box.com/pricing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6ca654b1-5613-43b1-b014-e4c65222346b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 16:22:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>After years of building popularity, software-as-a-service (SaaS) is becoming the predominant way that enterprises access core applications. Software that supports key areas of business, such as customer relationship management, will soon primarily be delivered via SaaS.  SaaS is a term used to describe software that is centrally hosted on virtualized infrastructure and served on demand via the internet to multiple organisations, as opposed to the traditional manner of businesses buying software and installing it on-premises.  Analyst house Gartner said that of the $149.9bn it estimates will be spent on enterprise application software in 2015, "the majority" will go towards modernizing, replacing or extending existing business software using SaaS.  "SaaS has become the model for software delivery at the moment, more than on-premise," said Laurent Lachal, senior analyst for infrastructure solutions with analyst house Ovum.  Core business processes supported by SaaS across businesses today include email and collaboration via offerings such as Microsoft's Office 365 and Google's Gmail, Customer Relationship Management via services such as NetSuite CRM and Salesforce, and human resources using services from Workday, SAP SuccessFactors and others. To a lesser extent, SaaS is also used to manage BI, document management and demand generation.  "Very few organisations trying to adopt an email or productivity solution would not be considering Office 365 or Google at this point," said Gartner VP and fellow Daryl Plummer.  Gartner estimates that by next year half of all CRM systems will be deployed via SaaS, with that figure rising to as high as 85 percent by 2025. Similarly, a survey by HR industry group HRO Today found that, when it comes to updating on-premise HR software, nearly as many firms are choosing to replace it with SaaS HCM as are choosing to upgrade those in-house systems.  The Forrester report Benchmark Your Enterprise Cloud Adoption found that in 2013 the median number of SaaS applications in use within enterprise was 11, and that respondents expected that number to rise by more than 30 percent each year over the following two years.  "This adoption rate is fueled by users acclimating to the agility and speed of SaaS solutions and the expansion of available SaaS offerings in the market. Today, nearly all categories of enterprise applications offer a choice of deployment, and in some categories, SaaS is overtaking older on-premises models," the report states.  SaaS can become the de facto delivery model for software supporting important business processes within a relatively small space of time; Forrester found that software supporting spend analysis within ePurchasing moved from 10 percent being delivered via SaaS to more than 70 percent within a decade.  The popularity of SaaS is also reflected in its status as the category of cloud service that handles the most workloads, relative to infrastructure as a service (IaaS) and platform as a service (PaaS). The estimate, made by the Cisco Cloud Index, gauges how cloud services are being consumed by users. By 2019, the report found, 56 percent of cloud workloads will be SaaS, up from 45 percent in 2014.   Image: Cisco As well a rise in the volume of SaaS being deployed, the criticality of the work carried out in the cloud is also changing, Gartner found in a 10-country survey in 2014.  "We've seen a real transition from use cases in previous surveys where early SaaS adoption focused on smaller pilot projects,"said Joanne Correia, research vice president at Gartner.  "Today, the projects are mission-critical and production-grade. This is an affirmation that more businesses are comfortable with cloud deployments beyond the front office running sales force automation and email."  Over the two years to 2016, Forrester predicts that enterprises will move roughly another 15 percent of applications into cloud environments, with spending on SaaS as a replacement for on-premise software soon overtaking that on SaaS as an add-on.  "Not only are businesses aggressively seeking SaaS alternatives, but they are also considering cloud for a broader category of services," says the Forrester report.  In the early days of SaaS, the report says that adoption was driven by new categories of applications that complemented existing core transactional software -- such as analytics and social and collaboration platforms. Today, however, Forrester finds that firms are replacing existing licensed software with SaaS, in areas such as sales force automation, CRM, human resource management, and eProcurement.  The popularity of SaaS in these key areas is reflected in the financials of the cloud specialists, with annual revenues at Workday steadily rising over the past five years to $975.8m and to $5.97bn at Salesforce.   Image: Forrester This appetite for SaaS CRM and HCM is seeing core modules within on-premise ERP systems being replaced with SaaS offerings, according to the PwC report Beyond ERP: New technology, new options. "New enterprise-grade applications are fast replacing old enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems as companies move to become more flexible and more mobile," says the PwC report. "These new applications can be integrated with traditional ERP software into "hybrid ERP" systems to enable specific functions such as human resources, supplier management, and e-commerce to operate with greater agility and independence from old-style IT organizations."  WHY ARE ORGANISATIONS CHOOSING SAAS? So why the interest in SaaS? According to Gartner's Plummer it's to do with the efficiency of the service model and companies being burned by failed on-premise upgrade projects.  "The main reason is the way we have been doing it isn't working that well," he said.  "Budgets are being decreased and the business units are already going out and buying SaaS without talking to the IT departments about it. They're finding that they get more choice, they get it faster, they get it with less hassle -- it's instant gratification if you will."  Given the choice between waiting years for major upgrades to be delivered, alongside the associated disruption and the complications of not breaking legacy dependencies, versus using a SaaS product that's constantly updated with no interruption to the service, companies will often choose SaaS, said Plummer.  SaaS often means swapping the capital outlay of buying IT infrastructure and licences upfront for the operational expense of paying an ongoing subscription. On top of this, it can be easier for firms to scale their subscription to SaaS offerings up and down as needed, while an in-house deployment requires infrastructure that firms can't easily divest themselves of. When all the costs are weighed up, SaaS will likely prove cheaper overall, he said.  "SaaS is more expensive in many cases, but that's only if you look at the direct price -- on-premises licensing versus cloud subscription. When you begin to look at those five-year upgrade cycles, you begin to look at all those customisations you spent money doing, you look at all the angst created at not being able to change what you want -- the cost [of SaaS] is not that much."  Ovum's Lachal agreed, stating the price tag for licensing or subscriptions are just the "tip of the iceberg" when it comes to what software truly costs a company.  "Yes, there is a cost element, but when you take the entirety of the cost, on top of being able to get the latest updates, as well as being able to move much faster, you get positive ROI," he said, adding that SaaS providers were more likely than in-house IT to regularly update not just the end-user software, but also the hardware and software stack underneath.   A ZDNet survey asked businesses to list their top three reasons for adopting SaaS. ANZ sample size was 580. Image: ZDNet The most common reasons for companies' reluctance to use SaaS are concerns over the security of the data and the service's reliability, said Gartner's Plummer. There have been a couple of high-profile outages of Amazon Web Service's cloud infrastructure platform this year, which in turn temporarily took down some of the many SaaS offerings built on top of AWS.  But, Plummer added, "our research finds the cloud is more secure than most datacenters and it's safer, so these are mostly just emotional reasons".  Emotional or not, they are a real roadblock for firms, said Ovum's Lachal.  "The center of gravity is that everything in the world is moving to the SaaS environment, absolutely, but there's still a lot of specific cases for which SaaS is less relevant: it can be for performance, security, or design reasons -- meaning that all the stuff that is really important cannot be moved."  Revelations by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden that US security services have widespread access to data stored on the servers of technology giants such as Microsoft and Google via programs such as PRISM have damaged confidence in the security of data stored in cloud services, as well as contributing to the EU Court of Justice's decision to scrap the Safe Harbor US-EU data sharing agreement that many cloud services rely upon.  Over the next three years, Snowden's revelation will cost US vendors $47bn in lost sales of public cloud services, according to estimates by Forrester.  Another common argument against public-cloud SaaS is that its offerings are generic and aimed at large numbers of companies, without the ability to cater to the specific needs of individual companies.   Firms rate their satisfaction with SaaS in a ZDNet survey. Image: ZDNet However, Gartner's Plummer says that businesses only need this level of control and customisation for a tiny proportion of the software they run -- usually when it relates to a core part of the business that differentiate the firm from its competitors. "If you have something in 2015 where you want to take tight control over how it's delivered, it better be really, really special or you should start to think about going back to live in your cave with the dinosaurs. Some things it's OK to keep on premises, but that's about maybe five to ten percent of the stuff that you've got."  SHAKING UP THE OLD GUARD As an increasing number of business workloads move into the cloud, vendors of on-premise software are having to reinvent themselves as cloud-first companies.  Database giant Oracle has been undergoing such a transition, with chairman and CTO Larry Ellison saying the company had filled in the last of "our major blocks" for its cloud portfolio as of June this year.  Not that it's plain sailing: in its most recent earnings, Oracle stumbled on software and cloud, which together were down two percent. Oracle also missed analyst expectations on cloud revenue, taking $611m instead of the forecast $630m.  Ellison explained away these problems as the company and the wider tech industry being in the middle of a generational shift. However, in contrast, a SaaS-first company like Salesforce, while having far smaller revenues than Oracle, is seeing earnings rise and rise, jumping to $1.635 billion for the most recent financial quarter.  SAP, traditionally a purveyor of on-premise ERP, has similarly declared itself to be a "cloud-first" company and is retooling its vertical and horizontal offerings to suit. The effort does appear to be starting to pay dividends, with the company reporting cloud subscription and support revenues of €600m in its most recent quarter, which, while still only a minor contributor to its €4.98bn revenues overall, is up 116 per cent on last year.  Also engaged in the same journey is Microsoft, which is heavily promoting its Office 365 SaaS offering and the fact that it has invested more than $15bn in building out cloud infrastructure, with its Azure platform available in 24 regions around the world.  Azure lags some way behind Amazon Web Services in size and public cloud market share -- AWS is bigger than its next four largest competitors. However, Microsoft is doing a good job of being the best of the rest, with analyst firm Forrester estimating that Azure has double the cloud platform revenue of its enterprise competition, including Oracle and IBM.  As you can see from their earnings, despite the shift to cloud, none of these traditional vendors are about to go under, as companies are still spending a lot to support and upgrade on-premise software. According to IDC, in 2015 firms will spend about twice as much on on-premise infrastructure than they will on that supporting public cloud, as they continue to invest in legacy in-house systems.  WHERE IS SAAS HEADING? The process of companies moving software to the cloud will happen in fits and starts, said Ovum's Lachal, and in many cases will involve SaaS being gradually phased into a firm, he added.  "It's not a black-and-white world where you have on-premise legacy and then you have SaaS applications; you have a whole continuum, as well as integration between on-premise on one hand and SaaS on the other.  This hybrid approach sees many firms running NetSuite as a second-tier ERP system alongside an on-premise SAP system acting as their core ERP, he said.  "We're living in a world where a lot of boundaries are blurring and the notion of SaaS is becoming more fluid. It's a very dynamic landscape."    JOIN DISCUSSION  Powered by Livefyre ADD YOUR COMMENT  RELATED STORIES   Apple IBM now has 100 iOS apps for business, enterprise; adding future Watson capabilities   Enterprise Software Half of all software in Brazil is pirated   Cloud Cloud Foundry launches code certification effort, IBM, HPE, Pivotal on board   Cloud Box, Salesforce establish more links between clouds  NEWSLETTERS  ZDNet Announce UK ZDNet's Announcements newsletter offers a mix of stories, special offers and members-only benefits.  Your email address   SUBSCRIBE SEE ALL  MORE RESOURCES  Power Better Business Agility in the Application Economy (French) White Papers from CA Technologies  READ NOW CFO Research: Thriving in the Digital Economy White Papers from SAP  READ NOW Effective Change Managment Through Service Automation (French) White Papers from Heat Software  READ NOW   PART OF A ZDNET SPECIAL FEATURE: ENTERPRISE APPS: THE NEXT GENERATION Research: Enterprise software rising with 69 percent usage A recent Tech Pro Research survey shows that 69 percent of businesses are currently using enterprise software, a 19 percent increase compared to 2014.   By Teena Hammond | December 1, 2015 -- 17:17 GMT (17:17 GMT) | Topic: Enterprise Apps: The Next Generation    Image: iStock/Andrew Ostrovsky The engine that supports many successful organizations is enterprise software with its complex and diverse functions. Information is critical to strategic endeavors, so the right tools are more important than ever before.  Enterprise software encompasses a variety of functions, including asset management, business intelligence, CRM utilities, data processing, databases, financial applications, identity management, retail software, process management and resource planning. It can run on either individual machines or on centralized servers, whether in-house, located in the cloud or a hybrid combination.  Because the utilization and management of enterprise software continues to remain at the forefront of key business initiatives, Tech Pro Research has surveyed readers on the topic for the past few years.  Read this year's full report from Tech Pro Research, Enterprise Software: Advantages, opportunities, challenges, and see how it compares to reports from 2013 and 2014.  Who is using enterprise software  Image: Tech Pro Research The use of enterprise software is increasing. More than two-thirds of survey respondents (69 percent) are currently using enterprise software, up from 50 percent in 2014's survey. And the larger the company, the more likely it is to use enterprise software, with 98 percent of companies with 1,000 or more employees either already using enterprise software, or planning to within the next 12 months, compared to 57 percent of companies with less than 50 employees.  New deployment of business functions for enterprise apps  Image: Tech Pro Research The most common functions where enterprise software was deployed during the past 12 months are databases (45 percent), storage (39 percent) and human resources (34 percent). Comparing back to 2014, mobile was chosen the most frequently at 44 percent, followed by big data at 31 percent and databases at only 12 percent.  As Scott Matteson wrote in the Tech Pro Research report, "It is interesting to note that the three least-picked selections in 2014 turned out to be the three most popular selections in 2015. Priorities and capabilities can change as plans merge with reality. It's also possible that enterprise software offerings in the mobile and big data sectors have not been on par with expectations, resulting in growth in other areas instead."  Preferred vendors The survey also focused on preferred vendors. Microsoft, Google and Adobe Systems were by far the top three preferred vendors. Microsoft is dominating the enterprise software scene with Office 365 as the choice in fourth place. Microsoft's popularity has risen from 43 percent in 2013 to 56 percent in 2014 to 63 percent in 2015.  Google has also demonstrated some amazing gains in this area as well; although it was commonly chosen as an 'other' choice in the past two years, in the 2015 report it was in use in half of the respondent organizations. Dropbox and LinkedIn enjoyed similar gains as well, barely mentioned last year and now in use at 26 percent and 22 percent of respondent organizations, respectively.  Conversely, vendors such as SAP, Oracle, JBoss (Red Hat) and CA Technologies have lost ground -- Oracle in particular, as it was among the top three vendor choices in 2013. In fact, usage of SAP and Oracle has been consistently decreasing since 2013, according to survey participants.  The future of enterprise software Overall, the report shows that enterprise software is in an excellent position to thrive. There is a solid vendor base and there are high levels of user satisfaction. Find out more about where enterprise software is heading in the next year and download the full report from Tech Pro Research, Enterprise Software: Advantages, opportunities, challenges.  Tech Pro Research is the premium content sister site to ZDNet and TechRepublic.  JOIN DISCUSSION  Powered by Livefyre ADD YOUR COMMENT RELATED STORIES   Big Data Analytics Health tech startup Clover raises $35 million from Sequoia Capital   Apple IBM now has 100 iOS apps for business, enterprise; adding future Watson capabilities   Enterprise Software Half of all software in Brazil is pirated   Cloud Cloud Foundry launches code certification effort, IBM, HPE, Pivotal on board  NEWSLETTERS  SEE ALL ZDNet CONNECT WITH US Facebook Twitter LinkedIn © 2015 CBS Interactive. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Cookies | Ad Choice | Advertise | Terms of Use | Mobile User Agreement  Visit other CBS Interactive sites:   TOPICS ALL AUTHORS GALLERIES VIDEOS ABOUT ZDNET MEET THE TEAM SITE MAP RSS FEEDS REPRINT POLICY LOG IN TO ZDNET | JOIN ZDNET MEMBERSHIP NEWSLETTERS SITE ASSISTANCE</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/after-years-of-building-popularity-software-as-a-service-s/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d817bf16-06cc-46bf-8e7c-6304b023d7a0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 16:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enterprise Apps: The Next Generation | ZDNet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Enterprise Apps: The Next Generation | ZDNet</h1><p>Inside this Special Feature: Enterprise Apps: The Next Generation</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/2f9ebf8d6469e24cea845a9901defe4a2d17f085.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.zdnet.com/topic/enterprise-apps-the-next-generation/?tag=nl.e004&amp;s_cid=e004&amp;ttag=e004&amp;ftag=TRE001a825</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1c6d958e-6064-4430-a62d-01a4deeaa22f</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 20:17:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Apps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Why Apps</h1><p>Most people agree that the internet has made our lives better. Instant global communication has transformed huge parts of our daily lives; we can find a piece of information instantaneously, buy practically anything with a couple of clicks, and order a cab with just a tap.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/902a29216ae759575ac44b39f6b0f4424a719553.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/56820f81-b196-4eb1-9333-afa265bd8247/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">56820f81-b196-4eb1-9333-afa265bd8247</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 16:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Voices"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>"Voices"</h1><p>So what is “Voices” ?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/voices/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3cc55b51-bf83-4199-8cc0-a75d61927da2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 20:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taking your Enterprise Mobile]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Taking your Enterprise Mobile</h1><p>Taking Your Enterprise Mobile: </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/taking-your-enterprise-mobile/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c7fd4203-688e-46a6-acf5-18e7c05ba2bb</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 19:44:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Social Collaboration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Social Collaboration</h1><p></p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/idecyde/social-collaboration/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a541e7e8-564c-45dd-aba5-3d243fd9c64e</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 19:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>